http://www.arbico-organics.com/category/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
X
$5 Off Your First Order*
Subscribe to be the first to hear about sales, promotions and special offers.* For new customers only. Cannot be combined with other coupons or discounts. Not valid on Fly Eliminators or Gift Cards.
Please enter a valid email address
2020 Winter Holiday Shipping Notice & Schedule
Customer Service
Contact Us
Request a Catalog
Suggest A Product
Shipping Info
Live Shipment Guarantee
Continue Shopping
Checkout »
LOGIN / REGISTER
0 items @ $0.00
800-827-2847
Fly Eliminators
Fly Eliminators® Programs
BUY NOW
Single Shipments
Get A Free Trial
ARBICO Organics Privacy Policy
(Effective January 11, 2010)
ARBICO Privacy Policy Visiting Our Website Learning What You Like At Your Service Information Secure Information Under Lock And Key Bringing Your Information Up To Date Information Sharing Information Sharing Is Up To You You May Remove Your Name from Our Lists At Any Time Your California Privacy Rights
Children's Privacy Statement
Collection Of Information Use And Disclosure Of Anonymous Information Ad Servers Security Partnerships Information Disclosed If Required By Law A Privacy Promise Privacy Policy Updates Questions Regarding ARBICO Privacy Policy
Since 1979, ARBICO has taken great pride in the relationships that it has developed with its customers. In keeping with this tradition, ARBICO is dedicated to protecting and respecting your privacy and handling any personal information we obtain from you with care and respect. This Privacy Policy is designed to answer your questions regarding our privacy policies and principles.
This is the Privacy Policy of Arizona Biological Control, Inc. (ARBICO). Our postal address is:ARBICO OrganicsP.O. Box 8910Tucson, AZ 85738.We can be reached via email at info@arbico.com or you can reach us by telephone at 800-827-2847.
Visiting Our Website
For each visitor to our website, our web server automatically recognizes only the IP address of your computer. When you make a purchase in the ARBICO Store, request a catalog, ask Dr. Buglady a question, sign up for the Go Organic! Newsletter, or answer one of our surveys, you may choose to give us basic information: name, email address, mailing address, ZIP code, phone, and credit card numbers(for purchases & samples only). This allows us to process your transactions more efficiently, and ultimately, to give you a higher caliber of customer service. When you visit our website, we may collect the following information: your Internet service provider's address, the name of the Web page directing you, as well as your clicks and activity on our site. This tracking data helps us understand how to make our site more responsive to our customers needs.
Learning About What You Like
We also gather customer information by observing the purchases you make. Think of it as a concierge service where your customer preferences are remembered for future consideration. By looking at your purchases in context with marketing demographics or with information from companies whose products and services you may be interested in, it helps us seek out products and services you may find relevant and unique. Similarly, other companies may also forward to us additional names, mailing addresses, and email addresses when we have news or product offerings that may be of special interest to their customers. In order to serve you better, we may at times contract with other companies to help us process information. For instance, their assistance can help us better fulfill customer orders, manage and enhance customer data, and comply with postal regulations.
At Your Service InformationThe information we collect is intended to help us provide better customer service and to improve communications.
The customer information you provide can help ARBICO provide greater security and inform you of products and services that may be of interest.
When a purchased item is not immediately available, many of our customers appreciate receiving an email to update the status of their order.
We may also need to contact customers by phone, postal mail, or email if questions occur regarding their orders.
When you shop at the ARBICO store, order from our catalogs, or visit us online, it is also an opportunity for you to provide us with information and feedback that helps us continue to expand our understanding of your needs and wants.
Secure Information Under Lock And Key
We take the following steps to protect our customers' personal information against loss, misuse, and alteration. We use encryption technology whenever receiving and transferring your personal information on our site.
When you make a purchase online, either a solid key or a locked padlock icon will appear in the lower right of your browser window.
This icon indicates that your transaction session is secured through Secure Sockets Layer (SSL).
If one of these icons does not appear, please contact ARBICO at 800-827-2847 to complete your order.
The ARBICO website uses SSL to communicate with secure browsers like Netscape, Firefox and Internet Explorer.
These browsers encrypt your credit card and personal information in a way that makes it extremely difficult for anyone to intercept and misuse them while they are being transmitted between your computer and our server.
Once you have completed your order online, our security procedures do not end.
We take further precautions to protect the security and privacy of the information stored on our computer networks.
Many of the systems which store your personal information are not connected to the Internet, reducing the likelihood of security breaches.
Our systems are also housed in secure facilities, and access to your data by our employees is limited to a "need to know" basis, controlled by password protected systems, and monitored for abuse.
If you are still unsure of giving your credit card over the Internet, please feel free to phone, fax, or mail your order to us.
For telephone ordering or assistance, please call 800-827-2847.
Our fax number for orders is 520-825-2038.
Or, send your order to: ARBICO, P.O. Box 8910; Tucson, AZ 85738.
In addition, ARBICO uses ScanAlert to check our website daily to ensure maximum security of our site.
Bringing Your Information Up To Date
Updating your contact information is quick and easy.
Simply contact us.
Include your previous and current full name, mailing address, email address and phone number. Updates can take from six to eight weeks to process from the date we receive your request.
Information Sharing
Information sharing can provide an important variety of consumer networking.
By providing new connections and introduction of new resources to our customers, you may discover new opportunities and products well suited to your interests and needs. With that end in mind, when you make a purchase, your customer information is shared with other select companies whose products and services you may find beneficial.
Information Sharing Is Up To You
We respect and appreciate that not all customers may wish to benefit from the opportunity to share information with other select companies. If you do not want ARBICO to share your customer information, please immediately contact us and we will remove your name from lists we share with other companies. After the six to eight week time period it takes to process your request, your information will no longer be shared. When contacting us, it is important to clearly state your request, including your name, mailing address, email address, and phone number.
It is important to understand that your information must be shared with some companies or online partners in order to receive their services.
By agreeing to share information, our customers may have the opportunity to participate in a broader array of services and offerings.
You May Remove Your Name From Our Lists At Any Time
To delete your name from the ARBICO email mailing list, or to have your name removed from the catalog mailing list, simply contact us. Be sure to provide your full name, mailing address, email address, and phone number. We appreciate your patience as it may take up to six to eight weeks to process your request from the date of receipt. When you make subsequent purchases at ARBICO, you may provide contact information for customer service only and request that your name not be forwarded to either mailing list.
Your California Privacy Rights
California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year.
If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with whom we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year.
If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:
ARBICO, P.O. Box 8910; Tucson, AZ 85738.
Children's Privacy Statement
ARBICO adheres to a strict privacy code regarding children and does not knowingly accept personal information from any child.
If it is brought to our attention that a subscriber is under age, we will immediately remove all personal and identifiable information from our records in compliance with the Online Children's Privacy Protection Act of 1998.
In addition, we will not disclose this information to any other companies.
This children's privacy statement explains our practices with respect to the online collection and use of personal information from children under the age of thirteen, and provides important information regarding their rights under federal law with respect to such information.
ARBICO's website is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do NOT knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen as part of our website. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen as part of our site, we will delete such information from our records. If we change our practices in the future, we will obtain prior, verifiable parental consent before collecting any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen.
Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen as part of our business, we also do NOT knowingly distribute such information to third parties.
We do NOT knowingly allow children under the age of thirteen to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information through our website.
Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen as part of our website, we do NOT condition the participation of a child under thirteen in the website's online activities on providing personally identifiable information.
Collection Of InformationFor each visitor to an ARBICO website, ARBICO's Web server automatically recognizes, collects and/or stores information such as the visitor's IP address/Domain name combination and any referring sites.
ARBICO may use several technologies to accomplish this. Examples of such technologies are cookies and Web beacons.
When you visit ARBICO's website or advertisements appearing thereon, use one or more of the ARBICO website services, or receive emails from ARBICO, we may use an industry-wide technology called "cookies" which stores certain information on your computer and which will allow us to customize your experience to better match your interests and preferences or to simply facilitate your signing in to use the services.
"Cookies" are small amounts of data that are stored on your computer.
They find their way to your browser via a Web server.
They sound friendly and helpful because they are.
They flag information about your activity on our website and store items in the shopping cart.
This information helps us improve our site and make it friendlier and easier to use.
We never use cookies to save passwords, credit card numbers or other highly confidential information.
Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored.
However, if you block or erase cookies, we may not be able to restore any preferences or customization settings you previously specified, and our ability to personalize your online experience would be limited.
Please refer to your browser instructions or "help" screen to learn more about these functions.
ARBICO may also itself use, or engage third parties to use, Web beacons for researching certain usage and activities on our website.
The information collected by ARBICO or requested from third parties through these Web beacons is in an aggregate, non-individually identifiable form and is used to find out more about users including demographic information and usage patterns for more accurate reporting and to improve the effectiveness of our marketing.
ARBICO may also itself use, or engage third parties to use, pixel tags or other technology to research or track your usage activities with respect to emails from us.
ARBICO may ask you to provide "personal information", meaning individually identifiable information such as your email address, name, mailing address, telephone number, credit card number, or persistent identifier (such as a customer number held in a cookie) which is associated with individually identifiable information, to enable you to participate in contests, chat rooms, on bulletin boards, to fill out a registration, or to order products and services using this site. ARBICO may combine the information you provide on our website with information we may collect offline from you or from third parties so that we can more effectively tailor our site, services and offerings to you.
Use And Disclosure Of Anonymous Aggregated InformationARBICO may also collect, aggregate and maintain anonymous information about you, such as your hobbies, interests, purchasing habits, music preferences, and the like.
This data can then be used to tailor ARBICO's promotions, advertising, and communications to deliver a better experience for you.
ARBICO may also share such aggregate information with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties; for example, to inform them about the percentage of male/female visitors to our site or the percentage of home gardeners vs farm owners, etc.
Ad Servers
With respect to Ad Servers, ARBICO does not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies.
Security
ARBICO makes reasonable efforts to maintain the security of your personal information in order to prevent unauthorized access to it through the use of technology and internal procedures.
However, ARBICO does not guarantee that unauthorized access will never occur.
Partnerships
We currently contract with online partners to help manage and optimize our Internet business and communications.
We use them to send emails that you have agreed to receive.
Web cookies are used in those email messages and at our website to help us measure the effectiveness of those emails.
You can "opt out" of this email cookie at any time by deleting your name from the ARBICO email mailing list.
We reserve the right to change email providers at any time.
We may also contract with other partners to help us assess visitation to the ARBICO site.
To do this, we place small pixel tags and cookies on our site. While these do allow for tracking of your visits, the data retrieved cannot be used for any reason without our authorization.
We control how that data may and may not be used.
Information Disclosed If Required By Law If required by law, ARBICO may provide any and all information we have about you to law enforcement or other government agencies, pursuant to a subpoena, warrant, or other order by a court of competent jurisdiction.
In all cases, we will require written documentation of the request, proof of the identity of the law enforcement official making the request, and we will take reasonable steps to authenticate the validity of the request.
Any law enforcement or government agency request submitted with less than a court-issued order will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis according to the need and urgency, as well as the particular law enforcement agency making the request.
A Privacy Promise We support and adhere to the guidelines and practices adopted by the Direct Marketing Association's "Privacy Promise." In so doing, we agree to comply with a customer's request to not share their information with other companies or to contact them for marketing purposes by postal mail, telephone or email.
If at any time, as a customer, you believe ARBICO has not complied with its Privacy Policy, please contact us. You may also contact the DMA's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at mgoldberger@the-dma.org, state or local chapters of the Better Business Bureau, state or local consumer protection office, The Federal Trade Commission by phone at 202-FTC-HELP (202-382-4357) or electronically at http://www.ftc.gov/ftc/complaint.htm. Privacy Policy Updates Efforts to bring new services, ideas and partners to benefit our customers may make it necessary for us to create a new Privacy Policy.
If this occurs, we will post the new policy on our website and also inform you via our direct mail communications. Once posted, the new policy will go into effect immediately, replacing any previously stated policy. ARBICO may also amend our current Privacy Policy at any time.
If we amend this Privacy Policy to permit material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you of such amendment by sending you an email at the last email address that you provided us, and/or by prominently posting notice of such amendment on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy.
Any such amendment to this Privacy Policy will be effective thirty (30) calendar days following either our dispatch of an email notice to you or our posting of notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy.
Please note that, at all times, you are responsible for updating your personal information to provide us your current e-mail address.
In the event that the last email address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any other reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the email containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the amendment described in the notice.
In any event, an amendment to this Privacy Policy may permit material changes in the way we use and share personal information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of such amendment.
If you do not wish to allow such material changes, you must so notify us (in the manner we specify) prior to the effective date of the amendment.
If you provide us this notice, we may choose to deactivate your account.
Please be advised, however, that, regardless of whether you provide such notice to us, any such amendment to this Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information that you provide us on or after the effective date of such amendment.
The effective date of this ARBICO Privacy Policy is January 11, 2010. It replaces all prior privacy policies issued by ARBICO. We reserve the right to change the ARBICO Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will be reflected in the updated version displayed at our corresponding website. Questions Regarding ARBICO Privacy Policy If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, we will do our best to answer them. Here's how to contact us: Email: info@arbico.com
Postal: P.O. Box 8910, Tucson, AZ 85738 Phone: 800-827-2847 (Customer Service) Fax: 520-825-2038 Hours of Operation: Monday-Friday, 8am-5pm, Mountain Standard Time
Our Store
Free Shipping
Fly Eliminators® - Biological Fly Control
Beneficial Insects
Pest Control Solutions
Disease Control
Growing Supplies
By Crop Type
Sales and Customer Service:
©2020 ARBICO Organics. All Rights Reserved.
